罗彻福德夫人 王后一定满心欢喜
How happy her Majesty must be, Lady Rochford.
我看她整日莺歌燕舞 喜不自胜
It seems to me she does nothing but dance and rejoice!
卡尔佩珀先生 她笑逐颜开 这理所当然
She has every reason to be happy, Mr. Culpepper.
她集国王万千宠爱于一身
The King spoils her.
他几乎每日都为她购置华服宝饰
Almost every day he buys her new dresses or jewels.
想尽万般方法讨她欢心
It seems he cannot treat her well enough!
我猜国王也同样春风满面吧
I presume the King is also very happy?
国王陛下简直如获新生
His Majesty seems like a new man.
他清晨五点多就起床 七点做弥撒
He rises between 5 and 6 am, attends Mass at 7,
一大早骑马打猎 十点回宫就餐
rides out early to hunt, comes back at 10 for dinner,
下午处理朝政
and attends to business in the afternoon.
我想他是意欲保持旺盛精力
I think his new rule of living is intended to keep him fit
你能心领神会吧
if you understand me.
如果他想取悦她 就得练就强健体魄
I suppose he would needs be fit, if he wants to satisfy her.
她魅力四射 引人注目
She is very... appealing.
卡尔佩珀先生 她只是个傻瓜
She's just a fool, Mr. Culpepper.
一个天真烂漫的小傻瓜
A sweet little fool!
罗彻福德夫人 你近况如何
How about you, Lady Rochford?
乔治·博林故去已有时日
It's been some time since George Boleyn's death;
- 你还未曾改嫁 - 没有
- You've not remarried? - No.
陛下 萨福克公爵求见
The Duke of Suffolk, your Majesty.
查尔斯 我要给你看样东西
Charles, I have something I want to show you.
我刻了枚纪念章 以此铭记我的婚姻
I've had a medal struck to commemorate my marriage.
[拉丁语]"亨利八世: 至我无刺的玫瑰"
"Henricus VIII: Rutilands rosa sine spina."
"你是我无刺的玫瑰"
"My rose without a thorn."
克里维斯的安近况如何
Tell me: how is Anne of Cleves?
她已定居新宅
I believe she has settled into her new estates,
并对陛下的仁慈慷慨
and shows every sign of being grateful
满怀感激之情
for your Majesty's charity and generosity.
我还获悉 她同陛下的女儿们
I also understand that she has maintained her relationships
仍时相过从
with your Majesty's daughters
常邀她们一起用餐
and often asks them to dine with her.
莱斯利
Risley.
- 陛下 - 写信给安女士
- Majesty. - We shall write to the Lady Anne
感谢她让我们得偿所愿
to thank her for being so conformable,
并向她保证 若她保持此道
and to assure her that if she continues in this way,
我们将视她为挚友
she will find in us a perfect friend,
并尊她为我最挚爱的妹妹
content to repute her as our dearest sister.
遵旨
Majesty.
夫人对你的态度有所改观吗 查尔斯
Does the Duchess love you any better, Charles?
看似如此
She seems to...
但只是表面文章罢了
but only for the sake of appearances.
我当如何帮你 查尔斯
How can I help you Charles?
待她欲再次与我行房
Well, when she consents to make love to me again...
造一枚勋章以示纪念吧
strike a medal to commemorate it!
- 夫人 - 萨里大人
- My Lady. - My Lord Surrey.
我一直期待着您的来信
I had rather trusted to hear from you.
为何
Why?
上次我们共进晚餐时 你让我以为…
When we supped together, you gave me to suppose that...
卡尔佩珀先生
Mr. Culpepper.
陛下
Your Majesty.
你以为什么 大人
That I what, my Lord?
以为你会施恩
That you would oblige me
满足我的欲望
and accommodate my desire.
如果让你有此误会 那么非常抱歉
If I gave you that impression I am truly sorry.
我并无此意
It was far from my intention.
为我侍寝吧
Sleep with me.
您不知我是何人吗
Don't you know who I am?
当然知道
Of course I know who you are.
那您可知家夫是谁
And you know who my husband is!
当然 他是西摩家的人
Yes I do! He's a Seymour.
彼之家族如狼
His family are wolves.
吾之家族则似虎
Mine are lions!
抱歉 我的追求太低了
Forgive me for aiming so low!
大人 陛下要见您
My Lord, his Majesty wants to see you.
赫福德伯爵参见陛下
The Earl of Hertford, your majesty.
真希望我能和你们一样欢快舞蹈
I wish I could go dancing like all of you!
只要音乐响起
Whenever I hear the music,
尘世一切繁务便一下子微不足道
I feel like nobody has a care in the world!
看看这些公文
Look at my cares!
曾有一人 能帮我打点好一切
I had someone once who could take care of all of this!
但他已不在了
But now he's gone!
吾儿可好
How is my son?
爱德华王子一切安好 健康茁壮
Prince Edward is very well. He is a strong and healthy boy.
不辱他父王的荣光
He does his father proud.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
他定能很快成为其他王子的楷模
I trust he will soon be followed by other princes.
我另有任务给你
I'm making you a new appointment.
我将封你为中将 出使北方
I'm making you Lieutenant General to the North.
近日多有逆贼
Recently, there's been too many incursions
从苏格兰向我大英进犯
over the border from Scotland into England.
我要你面见我的表亲 苏格兰之王
I want you to deal with my cousin, the King of the Scots,
让他下令停止进犯
and I want these incursions stopped.
如若不然
If he does not stop them,
我明确授命于你
you have our express permission
大举进犯他国国界
to harry and persecute the people on his side of the border
直至你觉得合适为止
with as much aggression and as much force as you see fit.
明白
I understand.
如果时机合适 我也许会和詹姆士国王会晤
We might, in time, meet our cousin, King James.
众所周知 他也许是大智若愚
For all we know, he may not be as stupid as he appears.
但现在
But for now,
我责成你去确保苏格兰
I am trusting you to ensure that the Scots cease their...
停止他们的无礼之举
impertinence.
凯瑟琳
Katherine!
天啊 继续
Oh God, oh fuck me!
凯瑟琳
Katherine!
继续 别停 用力…
Oh, fuck me... oh yes... oh yes...
- 凯瑟琳 - 啊 爽
- Oh, Katherine! - Oh yes... oh yes...
天啊
oh God...
别停下来
Oh just fuck me...
继续 再多说点
Go on! Tell me more!
我答应她不会外传
I promised her I wouldn't.
亲爱的琼 你可以对我知无不言
Dearest Joan, you can tell me.
我负责一切与王后有关的事宜
I'm responsible for everything to do with the Queen.
所以我得知道一切
So, I have to know everything.
这样我才能保护她
That way, I can protect her.
所以 你俩受公爵夫人庇护
So... when you both lived at Lambeth,
住在朗伯斯的时候
under the protection of the Duchess,
到底发生了什么
what exactly happened?
有两个护花使者
There were these two Gallants.
一个叫弗朗西斯·迪尔罕
They were called Frances Dereham
另一个叫爱德华·瓦德格拉夫
and Edward Waldegrave,
他是伯爵夫人的随从
who was a Gentleman in Waiting upon the Duchess.
总之
Anyway,
夜深人静之时 他们会设法
they found a way to call, secretly, at night,
与凯瑟琳和我幽会
upon Katherine and me.
整晚流连于我们床榻之上
And they would lie in our beds all night.
你和沃尔德格雷夫
You with Waldegrave
凯瑟琳和那位弗朗西斯·迪尔罕
and Katherine with this Francis Dereham?
没错 正是如此
Yes. That's how it was.
两位先生待你们如何
And what would these gentlemen do to you?
没人说闲话吗 无人知晓吗
Didn't anyone say anything? Didn't they find out?
若说是迪尔罕待她如妻
Well, if Dereham used her as a man doth his wife,
也不过是她自以为和他有白首之盟
it was only because she thought herself already betrothed to him.
仿佛约定俗成
Like on a promise.
他们的情史可不短
It went on between them a long time.
还有 你会保密的吧
Still, you won't tell anyone, will you?
你绝不透露半点
You won't say anything?
她要我发誓保密
She made me swear!
我会守口如瓶
No. I won't say anything.
早安 真是个好天气
Good morning! It's a lovely day today!
走开 别挡路
Come on! Get out of my way!
你乱看什么
What are you looking at?
要八加仑
Take a bushel!
滚开 你这贱人
Clear out of here, you fucking slut!
你在干什么
What in God's name are you doing?!
来见识下真正的女人吗
Starin' at a real woman, are you?
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
大人好身手
Good sport my Lord, good sport!
太过分了
Ain't right!
陛下 萨里伯爵因妨害公共秩序罪被关押
The Earl of Surrey has been jailed for public disorder, your majesty.
伯爵仍坚称自己为"上帝之鞭"吗
The Earl maintained he was the scourge of God?
是的 陛下
Yes, your Majesty.
还把伦敦称作"不知羞的婊子"
And called London itself "a shameless whore"?
是的 他的确这么说
Yes. He did indeed so.
他对大斋节时开荤一事作何解释
What about eating meat during Lent?
他说自己有权例外 只是
He told us he had a licence to do so. But...
但说无妨
But what?
加德纳主教怀疑
Bishop Gardiner suspects
萨里伯爵所食之肉是在万圣堂附近
my Lord Surrey of obtaining his meat on the black market,
通过蜜巷集市的新教徒屠夫
from some evangelical butchers in Honey Lane,
从黑市上购得
near the church of All Hallows.
陛下 这间万圣堂
This same church, your Majesty,
也有散播异教邪说
is suspected by some of secretly sowing
窝藏路德异教徒之嫌
and setting forth Lutheran heresies,
更有甚者 蓄意藐视斋戒律
and of deliberately flouting the fasting laws. Pound it back!
真没想到萨里是个异教徒
I never thought Surrey could be a heretic.
他父亲像是个天主教徒
His father is closer to a Papist...
至少在我面前装得很好
although to my face, he pretends otherwise!
若陛下恩准
His Grace and I would be inclined,
吾等臣子
with your Majesty's permission,
愿对伯爵之事
to examine the Earl more closely
进行深入彻查
on these fundamental matters.
你们想借机打压吗
You want to torture him?
不 马上放了他
No. Release him, for now.
要开始筹备新年了
We should make plans for the New Year.
是 陛下
Yes, your majesty.
我想宣玛丽公主进宫
I would like to invite the Lady Mary to court.
还想邀请克里维斯的安
I'd also like to invite Anne of Cleves
参加新年宴会
for New Year's celebrations.
拿过来 系紧
Bring that through. Fasten it here.
好的 到这边来
That's it. Bring it around this way.
两杆
Two rods!
女士们 这是国王赏赐的礼物
My Lady, here are your presents from the King.
是礼物啊
Presents!
真美
So beautiful!
看呐 多鲜亮 闻闻看
Look! So shiny! Smell!
玫瑰花香 真好
Smells of roses! It's lovely.
太漂亮了
It's perfect!
王后 看啊
My Lady! Look!
天呀
Oh my!
王宠如此隆厚
His Majesty spoils you!
我知道
I know he does!
难道我不值得他如此相待吗
But am I not worth it?
摸摸看 柔软无比
Feel it, it's so soft.
我是英国王后
I am the Queen of England.
是金子 我爱金子
Oh gold! I love gold!
这与我的裙子很配
It goes with my dress.
- 圣诞快乐 女士们 - 圣诞快乐 陛下
- Happy Christmas, Ladies. - Happy Christmas, your Majesty.
我们这是要去哪儿
Where are we going?
还有更多礼物呢
There are more presents.
还有啊
More?!
意下如何
What do you think?
太漂亮了
They're beautiful.
这是克里维斯的安所赠之礼
They were sent ahead by Anne of Cleves as a gift.
她将于明日抵达
She arrives tomorrow.
克里维斯的安
Anne of Cleves?
是的 我邀她前来共度新年
Yes. I've invited her for New Year.
你不会介意吧
You don't mind, do you?
当然不会介意
No, of course I don't mind.
臣妾悉听陛下吩咐
Your Majesty must do as you will.
但你觉得我会喜欢她吗
But...will I like her,
那个克里维斯的安
this Anne of Cleves?
明日自会知晓
Wait and see.
但愿玛丽公主高雅华贵胜过昔日
I hope the Lady Mary will be more gracious than before.
众位大人 玛丽公主驾到
My Lords, Lady Mary.
陛下
Your majesty.
吾之爱女 玛丽
My beautiful daughter, Mary.
向王后请安
Say hello to the Queen.
夫人
Madam.
玛丽公主 见你再次回宫 我欣喜不已
Lady Mary. I am very glad to see you back at court.
感谢陛下所赠厚礼
Thank you for my gifts.
依然一如既往阔绰大方
Your Majesty, as always, is more than generous.
查尔斯
Charles.
安女士
Lady Anne.
大人
Your Grace.
我犹记您当年授我牌艺
I remember that you once taught me to play cards.
我一直心存感激
I am very grateful.
多亏您的教导 让我收获颇丰
As a result of your tuition, I have won a fortune!
各位大人
My Lords,
克里维斯的安女士驾到
Lady Anne of Cleves!
安女士
Lady Anne,
欢迎来我宫中一聚
welcome to my court.
陛下 圣诞快乐
Your majesty! Happy Christmas.
请让我为你介绍我的新妻
Allow me to introduce to you my new wife,
凯瑟琳王后
Queen Katherine.
安女士
Lady Ann.
王后陛下
Your majesty.
能瞻仰陛下容颜 实属三生有幸 无上荣光
What a great privilege and honour it is for me to be presented to you.
我实在难掩激动
I am so delighted.
您的到来 我们欢迎之至 安女士
You are very welcome to court, Lady Anne.
您所赠汗血宝马 我们甚为感激
We thank you so much for the two fine horses you sent,
并祝愿您来年顺心愉快
and wish you a very happy New Year.
谢谢 王后陛下
Thank you, your Majesty.
窃以为我们当共同祝愿
I think we should all be merry!
正合吾意
Yes!
女士们 阁下
Ladies. Excellency.
你身体不适吗
You are not well?
近日身受痛风困扰 玛丽公主
These days I suffer a little from gout, Lady Mary.
- 快请坐吧 - 谢谢
- Please sit. - Thank you.
你一直是我最信任的朋友
You are and always have been my most faithful
忠贞可靠 当世无人能及
and truest friend in all this world.
你如要离去 我实在无法承受
I could not bear it if you were ever to leave here.
他不该与安女士离婚
He ought not to have divorced the Lady Anne.
并非我与她相交更深
Now that I know her better,
我认为她甜美可人 雍容华贵
I think she is perfectly sweet and gracious.
尽管如此 玛丽公主
Nevertheless, Lady Mary,
恐怕您还是要与新王后建立友好的关系
I fear that you will have to reconcile yourself to the new Queen.
恐难为止 我讨厌她
No, I will not. I hate her.
也许我的建议于您而言犹如鸿毛 无足轻重
Then, perhaps, after all, you do not require my advice any more.
夫人 不知您可有家兄爱德华的消息
My Lady, I wanted to ask if you had any news of my brother Edward?
他很好
He's well enough.
身受寒气所侵 潮气所扰 但依然安好
Cold, but well. Wet, but well.
显然 北部冷雨频繁 淤泥随处皆是
Apparently, it always rains in the north, and the mud is free.
不知他有何动作
Will he see some action?
我想他一定会猛击苏格兰人的痛处
I believe he intends to punish the Scots for their terrible wickedness.
听上去确属家兄作风
That sounds very like my brother.
可惜在这方面你不及他 托马斯爵士
If only you could be more like him, Sir Thomas.
何出此言呢
What do you mean?
余之夫君 心之所想 志在必得
My husband always takes what he wants.
女士们 失陪一下
Ladies, you must forgive me.
我今日早起外出打猎 略感疲惫
I rode out early to hunt this morning and am very tired.
明日 我们再共进晚餐
We shall dine again together tomorrow evening.
- 安女士 - 是 陛下
- Lady Anne. - Your majesty.
我美丽的妻子
My beautiful wife.
留下来 尽情享受舞会的快乐吧
Now, I must insist you stay to enjoy the dancing.
小卡
Boy!
玛丽公主
Lady Mary!
愿大家尽兴 新年快乐
I bid you all a good night. Happy New Year!
新年快乐 陛下
Happy New Year, Your Majesty!
安女士 需要添些酒吗
I wonder... will you have some more wine, Lady Anne?
王后陛下如此建议 我荣幸之至
With pleasure, if Your Majesty will.
好
Yes.
添酒
Wine.
王后陛下 请用
Your majesty.
谢谢
Thank you!
安女士 请用
Lady Ann.
陛下曾透露 伊丽莎白公主
His Majesty tells me that his daughter,
时而会去探望你
the Lady Elizabeth, sometimes comes to see you.
你觉得她如何
How do you find her?
迷人极了
Oh, she is charming.
聪明美丽
So clever. And so beautiful.
惹人怜爱
And so very affectionate.
与她见面 总令人心情愉悦
It is always a pleasure to see her.
我不欲再嫁
You see, I have no desire to remarry,
因此 膝下便无儿女
so I am sure I will never have any children of my own.
小伊丽莎白 如女儿般贴心
I think a little that Elizabeth is like a daughter to me.
相较之下
Surely it is so
比起王后之位 如此乖巧伶俐的女儿
to have had her as a daughter would have been
带给我更多欢愉
a greater happiness to me than ever being Queen.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ!
好多了
That's better.
能问陛下一个问题吗
May I ask Your Majesty a question?
说
Go on.
陛下为何邀请克里维斯的安女士赴宴呢
Why did Your Majesty invite Lady Anne of Cleves for Christmas?
对她 我心有怜惜
I like her, after all.
她是言而有信之人 小卡
She keeps her promises, boy.
王后陛下 请
Majesty? Come!
琼·布尔默偷偷告诉你什么
So, what did this Joan Bulmer tell you?
她说…
She said that
每天夜里 迪尔罕会潜入凯瑟琳的香闺
on the nights Dereham visited Katherine's bed,
时而带些美酒
he would bring with him wine,
草莓 苹果 或其他小食
strawberries, and apples,
二人宴飨尽饮 好不乐乎
and other things to make good cheer.
然后呢
And then?
然后…
Then...
怎么样呢
What then?
激情热吻
There would be kissing
宽衣解带 翻云覆雨
and...he would pull down his hose and lie down with her.
莺歌燕舞
And the two of them would
如胶似漆 共赴巫山
hang by their bellies like two sparrows.
来拿啊
Come here.
莺歌燕舞
And the two of them would hang by
如胶似漆 共赴巫山
their bellies like two sparrows.
你为何在此
Why are you here?
如家兄一般
Taking what I want.
夺取吾心所欲
Just like my brother does.
他擅长如此
Just like he's always done.
若我拒绝呢
And what if I don't want it?
若我唤来侍卫呢
What if I call my servants?
你不会 知道为什么吗
You won't. And you know why?
因为我们是一类人
Because you hate my brother.
你恨我哥哥
You hate him almost as much as I hate him
但除我之外
but you can't tell anyone
你根本无处诉苦
except me.
好吧 西摩先生
Well, Mr. Seymour,
就寝吧
come into my bed.
敬请细细品味汝兄之物
Enjoy what your brother enjoys.
相较之下 定当妙趣横生
It will be interesting to compare you.
我信唯一的上帝 我万能的父
Credo in unum Deum patris omnipotentum.
我信唯一的上帝
Credo in unum Deum patris
我万能的父
Patris omnipotentum.
公主殿下 王后驾到
My Lady! My Lady! The Queen is here!
- 王后陛下 - 玛丽公主
- Your Majesty - Lady Mary
本宫亲临到此 是想问你为何不能
I have come here in person to ask you
对作为英格兰王后的本宫
why you will not show me the respect which as Queen of England
施以合乎尊卑礼数的敬重
I am entitled to expect even from you.
我早就注意到 和其他人一样
I noticed, as did everyone else,
你们都对克里维斯的安女士相当敬重
that you show the greatest respect to the Lady Anne of Cleves,
而并不在乎她现在微不足道的身份与地位
even though she is now just a private person and worth no account.
恕我冒昧 可是安女士
Forgive me. But surely the Lady Anne is
确实值得我们每个人敬重
worthy of every respect?
她举止雅贵 仪态雍容
She carries herself with great dignity
端庄贤淑 秀外慧中
and also modesty,
并且她一心侍奉陛下 别无他图
and desires nothing more than to please the King her Lord.
你是说我没有尽心侍奉陛下吗
Do you mean I do not try to please him?
我觉得您除了玩乐享闲 亦无他求
I think you desire almost nothing else than pleasure!
终日只知锦衣华扮 嬉闹宫闱
It pleases you, it seems, to do nothing but wear
秀舞寻欢
pretty clothes and dance.
众人虽觉得这种行为轻浮放浪
Some people may think that frivolous,
无奈君王伴偶的身份却覆之以伪圣的外衣
in the consort of a King whose flesh is also sacred.
倘若陛下认为我轻浮放浪
If his Majesty thought me only frivolous,
又为何要纳我入宫
Why did he marry me?
母以子贵 陛下看重的是您的生育能力
You are thought capable of bearing sons.
这是所有君王的相同之处
Unfortunately, for all the King's attentions,
可我看您至今仍未怀有身孕
I see you are still not pregnant.
如此下去 陛下迟早会冷落你
In any case, he will soon tire of you.
走着瞧吧
You'll see.
你又怎么样呢
And what about you?
我怎么了
And what about me?
我觉得你不过是妒火中烧
I think you're jealous.
你嫉妒我 因为你年老色衰
You're jealous because you're much older than me
却依然待字闺中
and you're still not married.
闺深夜长 等着做一辈子老处女吧
Perhaps you'll never be married, and will grow old a maid!
你怎么敢对我如此出言不逊
How dare you speak to me like that.
我就是敢 因为我有权力
I dare because I can.
我的权力还远不止这样
And I can do something else, too.
出于对你失敬于本宫的惩罚
As punishment for your lack of respect towards his Majesty's wife,
我要削减你身边的两名侍女
I am removing two of your maids from your service.
祝你好运 玛丽女士
A good day to you, Lady Mary.
敬与挚爱
Here's to love.
敬与凯瑟琳 英格兰王后
To Katherine, Queen of England.
上帝保佑 你们不久便能喜得龙种
And, God willing, may you soon be ripe with children.
非常感谢 你们两位
Thank you. Both of you.
你真是仁慈可人 安女士
You are so kind, Lady Anne
还有我温慈的陛下
and my gracious lord.
我这辈子永远都是最快乐的人
I am the most happy I have ever been in my whole life.
我有礼物送给你
I have a gift for you.
天呐
Oh my God!
我能看看吗 王后陛下
May I please see it, your Majesty?
这是什么 还有惊喜吗
Oh, what's this? Not more presents?!
喜欢吗
Do you like them?
我爱死它们了
Oh, I just adore them.
真漂亮
They're so pretty.
- 可是… - 怎么
- Oh! But... - But?
陛下可否准许我与安女士
With your Majesty's permission, I would like
分享这份礼物
to share these gifts with the Lady Anne.
和我吗 还是别了
With me?! No!
可以吗
May I?
当然
Of course.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you!
真可爱
So sweet!
它们是你的了
They're yours.
- 感谢你 凯瑟琳 - 新年快乐 安女士
- Thank you, Katherine! - Happy New Year, Lady Anne,
你好吗 小家伙
Hello!
看它有多可爱
Hello. Isn't he sweet?
玛丽公主
Lady Mary!
您这是干什么
What are you doing?
我要回汉斯顿去
I'm going back to Hunsdon.
您得到陛下的准许了吗
Have you asked his Majesty's permission?
您为何要离去
Why are you leaving?
你没听说吗
Haven't you heard?
她要削减掉我两名侍女
She has removed two of my maids!
王后吗
The Queen?
只是因为我没对她表现出足够的敬重
Apparently I don't treat her with sufficient respect.
女士 请听我说 我相信
Madam, please. I am sure if you found some
您只需稍费心思以抚悦一下王后
small means to conciliate the Queen,
那样您的侍女们就能获准留下
then the maids would probably be allowed to remain...
不 为何我要如此
No! Why should I?
我不愿向她示好
I don't want to conciliate her.
她对您说了什么
What did she say to you?
她说
She said...
说我嫉妒她
that I'm jealous of her.
因为她已成婚
Because she is married
而我却没有
and I'm not.
而且我永远也不会
And may never be.
她不该说这些话
She ought not to have said such things.
不 可她说得没错
No, but they're true!
千真万确
They're true!
我亲爱的小姐
My sweet Lady.
我可怜的好小姐
My poor sweet Lady.
罗彻福德夫人
Lady Rochford.
国王陛下今日可好 卡尔佩珀先生
How is the King today, Mr. Culpepper?
陛下今日十分安好
He is very well,
他让我转达他的爱意
He sends you his love and
并希望您得到妥善的照顾和款待
hopes you are well looked after and entertained?
今日我本想去骑马 可天公不作美
I wanted to go riding today but the weather was too bad.
我很遗憾
I'm very sorry to hear it.
陛下希望您了解
His Majesty wants you to know
我军对苏格兰的战役
that the military campaign against the Scots has
大获全胜 他对赫福德大人十分满意
been a great success, and he is most pleased with Lord Hertford
也对在那里奋战的其余将领十分满意
and his other Captains, who performed well in the field.
在哪里
Which field?
我是指在战场
It means the battlefield.
我很欣慰
Ah. I'm glad.
- 欣慰 - 他们在战场上
- Glad? - That they did so well.
表现如此卓越
In the field.
还有事么 卡尔佩珀先生
Is there anything else,Mr. Culpepper
是 是的 这本书
Yes, yes. This book.
这本书是由一位理查德·琼斯所著
It was written by one Richard Jonas,
他是克里维斯的安夫人的随行人员
who came here to England in the train of Anne of Cleves,
显然他本想把此书敬献给他的女主人
and obviously meant to dedicate it to his mistress.
但现在 若能得陛下您的垂青
But now,with your Majesty's permission,
他愿将此书敬献给您
he would like to dedicate it to you.
什么书 给我
What is it? Give it me.
人类的起源
"The Byrthe of Mankind"?
这应该是第一本由英文撰写
I believe it's the first major work
关于助产学的书籍
on midwifery to be written in English.
助产学
Midwifery?
琼斯先生希望将此书献给最仁慈善良
Mr. Jonas would now like to dedicate it to the most gracious
优秀卓越 品德高尚的凯瑟琳王后
and in all goodness, most excellent, virtuous lady, Queen Katherine
托马斯
Oh! Thomas!
不知道那是什么感觉
I wonder what it would feel like?
你说的是什么
What what would feel like?
我想象着 带上美酒
I suppose I should go down to her with wine,
苹果和草莓去找她
apples, and strawberries,
尽管那些东西在此季节已难寻觅
although they are all out of season.
你是在说谁
Who are you talking about?
你觉得呢
Who do you think I'm talking about?
莺歌燕舞 如胶似漆
Hanging by their bellies like two sparrows!
- 你真的想要吗 - 什么
- Do you really want to? - What?
若你真想
If you do,
我能替你安排
I could arrange it.
大人
My Lord.
- 感谢上帝 公爵大人 - 怎么样了
- Thank God, your Grace! - What's happened?
来 快过来
Come. Come!
情况有多糟
How bad is it?
公爵大人 陛下腿上的溃疡
Your Grace, the ulcer on his
不幸再次阻塞
Majesty's leg has unfortunately become clogged again.
我们别无他法
We have no option but to
只能割开伤口挤去已积脓液
drain off the fluid which has collected there.
否则 只怕陛下性命堪忧
Otherwise-we fear for his Majesty's life!
请原谅 陛下
Forgive me, Majesty...
此次非比平常 大人
This is worse than ever before, your Grace.
若是陛下驾崩将会如何
What happens if the King should die?
你们要向上天祈求陛下能挺过去
Your race must pray to heaven that he does not.
可他的情况令人堪忧
But he looks likely to die!
我最担心的莫过于此
That is what I'm afraid of.
大人们 我对你们大失所望
My lords, I assure you that I am not content.
我曾给予你们信赖
I have relied upon you
委汝为我出谋划策
to inform and counsel me
然而 我却受到生生地欺骗
and yet I am the most deceived.
我对诸位如此信任 宠爱有加
I have trusted and favoured all of you.
可如今心生疑窦
I have formed a sinister opinion...
你们全都满嘴谎话
that most of you are liars
只顾溜须拍马 谋求一己私利
and flatterers who look only to your own profits.
我知道尔等居心何在
I know what you are plotting.
若神能助我一臂之力
And if God gives me the strength,
我必定教你们
I will see to it that none
阴谋挫败 一事无成
of your projects ever succeed!
克伦威尔之死令我扼腕
I mourn Cromwell's death.
我悲痛不已
Yes! I mourn him.
因为我察觉到手下臣子
I mourn him now that I perceive my Councillors,
捏造事实 以莫须有的罪名
by light pretext, and by false accusations,
害我处决了最忠诚的仆从
made me put to death the most faithful servant I ever had.
卡尔佩珀
Culpepper.
陛下 卡尔佩珀先生求见
Your Majesty, Mr. Culpepper is here.
谢天谢地 我能见陛下了吗
Thank God! May I see his Majesty?
抱歉 王后 陛下依然龙体欠安
Forgive me, my Lady, but his Majesty remains indisposed.
他让我转达对您的爱 并以此表明心意
He sends you his love and this as a token of it.
感谢陛下 不过…
I thank his Majesty, but...
陛下已有十天之久未曾召见我
it is ten days since I have been allowed into his presence.
他到底为何不愿见我
Why will he not see me? Why?
我可有触怒龙颜 冒犯圣意
Have I offended him in some way? What have I done?
他定然不再爱我如前
He cannot love me so much
否则怎会不闻不见
if he can so easily neglect me!
或许陛下早已移情别恋
Perhaps he has taken a mistress!
他是否另结新欢 卡尔佩珀先生
Has he taken a mistress, Master Culpepper?
所以才不召见我
Is that why he won't see me?
陛下 恕难奉告 抱歉
I cannot answer your Majesty. I'm sorry.
他们此刻在一起吗
Is he with his mistress now?
很好 既然你执意不讲
Very well. You may go, since you will not tell me anything,
眼看我伤心绝望 那就退下吧
even though you see how unhappy and miserable I am!
我愿意为您赴汤蹈火
You know I would do anything in the world,
在所不辞
anything...
只要您顺心遂意 笑颜常开
to bring you comfort and make you happy.
怡然自在 世所钦羡 您生当如此
More than any other woman, you deserve to be happy.
卡尔佩珀先生英俊潇洒
Mr. Culpepper is so handsome.
他爱上您了
He's in love with you.
爱上我？
In love?
是的 他亲口坦承
Yes. He has confessed everything.
他告诉我 他爱得神魂颠倒
He loves you madly. He told me so. He said
甚至愿为您献出生命
he would happily die for you!
他对您日夜牵挂
And that he thinks and dreams of you
朝思暮想
day and night.
萨里作了一首有关我们的诗
Surrey has written a poem about us,
在宫中广为传播
which is circulating the court.
有关我们
About us?
诗中怎么说
What does he say?
他称您为狼女
He calls you the wolf lady.
他当然就是狮子
Naturally, he is the lion.
说您设套诱捕他
He says you tried to entrap him
但高贵的野兽 绝不会受制于奸佞之徒
but he is too noble a beast to be tangled by such cunning hooks!
他还警告 如果您再敢图谋不轨
He also warns you that if you should cross his path again,
就让您打雁不成 反遭啄眼
he will feed on you as you meant to feed on him.
他还说我们杀害无辜 借此飞黄腾达
Oh, and he says that we rose high by murdering the innocent!
我愿意为您赴汤蹈火 在所不辞
You know I'd do anything in the world,
只要您顺心遂意 笑颜常开
anything...to bring you comfort and make you happy.
怡然自在 世所钦羡 您生当如此
More than any other woman, you deserve to be happy.
他想单独会见您
He wants to visit you. Privately.
谁
Who?
卡尔佩珀
Culpepper.
这怎么行 不可能
He can't! That's not possible.
当然可以
Of course he can!
不是有人半夜会过您吗
Just like that other one coming to you at night.
你都知道了
You know about that?
当然
Of course I know.
琼·布尔默告诉了我
Joan Bulmer told me.
这次也可如法炮制
And it can be just the same.
绝对保密
A secret.
神不知 鬼不觉
Nobody else need ever know...
国王不会知道
not the King,
谁都不会知道
not anybody!
你能保证吗
Are you sure?
来啊 来
Come! Come!